The Principality of Zeon
A gigantic space
citystate floating beyond the moon
Is dominated by
the Zabi royal family
Who are determined to control all of humanity
Attempting to
bring down their dictatorship
The Earth Federation has fought relentlessly
Against the
Zeons on Earth
And in outer space
Meanwhile
the White Base
which had survived the attack of a Zeon space cruiser
escaped from the
space colony side seven and descended to Earth
The young crew
unable to contact
Federation forces
must continue fighting
They must encounter one terror after another
Coming home
Here we go
It's strange to
feel direct sunlight
In the
space colony
the lights
diffuse with mirrors
I guess this
place is what they call nature
Mere I？
When people talk
of the open sky
I suppose this
is what they mean
Hey guys
seen Amuro？
He went to
see his mother
Kai，he'll be back
So that's why I
saw the core fighter
go figure
He just left
he said his hometown was about 30 kilometers away
Well，I'm
disappointed in him
Isn't he one of
Earth's elite？
It's really unfair to say that everyone who happens to live on Earth's elite
Amuro and his father stayed out in space for several years
He's never really
lived with his mother
so he's eager
to see her again
Just having a
place on Earth makes you elite
It seems like there have been a lot of air raids in this area
doesn't it？
I hope this
area is safe
I do wonder
There's been some
guerilla fighting
so I hear
I couldn't possibly imagine you getting hurt
mother
Let's have
another round
Huh？Who are you
kid？
This is my house
What？
Stop
But this brat
wasn't very…
Ah，shoot
it's empty
Sorry
we entered your
house without permission
but there
was no one here
kid
Nobody was here？
It's an
abandoned house
What？
You're lying
Mother
Mother？
Mother，huh？
He doesn't
believe me
Mother
Hey， maybe she
ran away from home
If you need to
be with Amuro
my dear
you'll have to
come with us right now
But going into
outer space is…
You'd change your mind if you took one look at the remarkable construction of Asie
I have to
show it to Amuro
I understand that
but I don't
think I can…
Forgive me
I could never get
used to living in outer space
Amuro
喂，嘿，呢
what's the matter？
What's wrong
little boy？
Miss your mommy？
Please pay me
This is all we
have to live on
Please
pay me for
that apple
Don't pick it up
lady
The soldier
he'll pick it up
Who's that？
Oh
hey，that boy
I'll say
that to my face
kid
I said pick
up the coin
and I meant it
You little…
What do you know？
If we wasn't here
patrolling the area
and protecting
people like we do
this town would
have become Zion property a long time ago
I remember，Amuro
that boy is a
friend of my daughter's
Please stop
He's just a child
What's that？
Stop what？
I'll give you
back your money
Please leave
that poor boy alone
The soldiers
who survived
were cut off
from the main force
No one would come
and help when they needed it
so that's what
happened to them
Or so…
it's so awful
I see
so…
Komalie's gone？
Yes
my daughter and my…
my husband
I wish I could
feel grateful being alive
but somehow I…
So
have you been
able to find your mother？
But
haven't you
gotten any letters from her at all？
So you don't know
that she's a volunteer at the refugee camp？
She's alive？
Yes
do you remember
the old church we used to go to？
Behind the hill
near the place
where you'd play with Komali？
Oh，thank you
Careful，please
Armoro
The enemy seems
to have completely retreated
If no Federation
fighters come out to greet us soon
Our guns will
start to rust
I'm crying
This is Lagoon
3 reporting here
Area 304
no activity
Roger
All hands
return to ship
Enemy
aircraft sighted
Ready antiaircraft batteries
Enemy？
It's approaching
from ten kilometres out at sea
And it's not
transmitting a friendly radio signal
Mr， Bright
What should I do？
Should I launch
the White Base？
No，if we try to
move right now
they'll spot us
more easily，Miri
That's true
We can't afford
to have them call for reinforcements either
We'll take the
initiative and shoot them down
Right
Core Fighter
ready to launch
You're
cleared for launch
Core Fighter
Proceed when
you're ready
Roger，I'm off
Something's coming
Enemy？
Looks like
a fighter
Wait
he's behind us
What？
Too late
Descend
This is it
my mother
is down there
Something's coming
It looks
like an airplane
you guys
Let's go look
Is it just my
imagination？
Or do you see a
Federation fighter？
That's
exactly what it is
This isn't good
Wow， cool
that's a real
fighter plane
Wait a minute， son
You're a soldier
from the Federation
right？
I don't know the
reason why you've come here
But could you do
us all a favour and hide that fighter？
But why？
I'm just
trying to…
Well son
your enemy's forward base is just beyond those mountains right over there
And they come to
check us out almost every single day
If they've
already seen you
it could
create huge problems
Could you hide
your plane for us please
son？
Yeah
I'll do it
right now
Is that Amuro？
Amuro？
Mother
Amuro
阿莫羅，媽
Excuse me
could you please
take care of the fighter plane now？
Yes，that's right
Amuro
go hide it quickly
Then the two of
us can spend some time together
I take it that
's your son？
Yes
Horrible
I had no idea how
far the Zeons would go
Then
you don't
know that father…
Hey
two soldiers
are coming here
Don't
move a muscle
okay？
咻，咻
Watch this
What kind of
fighter is that tailing us？
I don't know
Forward base
this is hot dog
patrol reporting
Enemy fighter
in our sight
Position Y207
Look，over there
What？
Gotcha
Oh no
fuel is leaking
it looks bad
Listen，Bright
They got my fuel
tank during the attack
I hit one of
their planes
but I lost it
You can't
confirm it？
No，I can't stick
around any longer
Operator
are you able to
figure out the enemy's flight path？
All I can tell you is that the enemy aircraft is heading southwest
Which means the
plane is heading toward Amuro's hometown
We must
contact him
Listen up， Ryu
can you get
back to the ship？
That's no
problem at all，but…
I'll have
Amuro do the rest
Alright， over
Sailor
send Amuro an
alert signal now
Hurry，Sir
Alright
Everybody
stay put
Nobody move now
Isn't anyone in
this place gonna speak up？
We heard that an
enemy fighter may have landed
Anyone have any
information to back up this report？
Hey
did you happen to
see an airplane？
You can
tell me，kid
Don't be afraid
and just tell me exactly what you saw
That's not nice
Look， I
have chocolate
Give me back
my mom and dad
Too bad
you lost your
chance to have some chocolate
Sorry， kid
Where's that
noise coming from？
How could they
page me at a time like this？
Where's that
noise coming from？
I don't know
I'm 89 years old
Hey，Ma'am
Who's that in
that bed over there？
Nobody，really
just one of the
injured that I'm helping to take care of
that's all
Let's see
He's my son
and he's
badly injured
Let's see if you
have nothing to hide
阿莫羅
阿莫羅？
It looks like
this soldier's still breathing
Get a doctor
Even those Zeons
could have children waiting for them at home
You've…
you've
grown so wild
Almero
I don't
even know you
I…
I can't believe
what you're saying
Mom
You'd rather
they got me？
Would you
prefer that？
It's war
I…
I know， but…
It's not
right for my son
to wave around
a gun like that
Oh， Mom
are you saying…
Are you saying…
You don't love me？
How can you？
How is it possible for a mother not to love her only son？
You're a liar
阿莫羅
What's happened
阿莫羅？
Uh
nothing
Right
this is an
emergency
A Zeon patrol
plane is headed your way
Roger that，Sailor
Amuro
What's happened？
You weren't raised to be such a terrible violent boy
Why can't you
be more gentle？
Like you
used to be
Can't you accept…
We're at war now
You're so cold
I'm ashamed to
call you my son
Is that it？ I'll get you， Where do you think you're going？ Are you heading for a face？
Heads up
the recon plane
didn't make it back
Commence
antiaircraft fire
launch the doms
I missed them
No way
Got Perry？
Great
they brought
Gundam with them too
Yeah
Hey，Amuro
You wanna try
a new challenge
and attempt a
midair conversion？
What？
Midair？
Yeah
A trial run
during battle should be fun
Go，It's a bad idea
Mr， Kai
We just installed
the docking parts that Lieutenant Matilda brought us
They haven't
even been tested
You just heard
Amuro say he wants to try it in midair
So we better do it
Maybe it's because I was never around all those years
All I know is he
wasn't like this as a boy
My little boy
wouldn't even hurt a fly
Distance 50 meters
Activate
docking searcher
Laser searcher synchronized
countdown
5、4、3、2、1
Gundam
module B released
Core change
Go for docking
Done，good one
Gundam
Module A released
Kai，watch it
I don't think it
's synchronised
That's Amuro
What in the world
is he doing out there？
Well
he's probably
going after the enemy base
What's the point of using our valuable ammunition on that backwater base？
And stupid Kai
what was
he thinking？
A midair docking
in front of the enemy without testing？
It's a careless
waste of our resources
You know we might
as well surrender to the Zeon forces right now
Right
that's enough
So you
think I'm wrong
do you？
No
You don't
want to stay
No，mom
it's not like that
I feel like I belong somewhere for the first time in my life
You are
his mother？
I want to thank
you for taking care of Amuro
Not at all
Amuro has saved
us on many occasions
Oh yes，really？
Earlier today
Amuro did an impressive feat under difficult circumstances
And we're all
proud of him
I see
Yes
now that
coming Amuro…
Well，we'll be
leaving shortly
all right？
Yes
Goodbye，mother
Take care
of yourself
I gotta go
Excuse us
I'm honoured to
have your son in our unit
The White Base crew aren't the only ones running short on weapons and supplies
Chief Quarren's booby trap strategy is enough to bring terror to Amuro and the entire crew
as they bravely
face off with Gundam
Will Amuro
survive the assault？
Mobile Suit Gundam
Next episode：
Time Be Still
Who will survive？
阿姆羅
振り向かないで
宇宙の彼方に輝く星は，阿姆羅
お前の生まれた故郷だ